







Data Engineer Technical Project Manager-Scrum - seeking for job opportunities in Data Warehouse, Big Data, Azure Data Engineering tools - Azure Data Factory, Azure Databricks, Azure Synapse analytics, Azure SQL, Azure DevOps. Test Lead, Test Manager



Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Designation: Technical Project Manager Data

Engineering team

Current Company: Dell International Services
Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Project Mgr-IT/Software

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Scrum Master, Project Manager, Application Programming, Project Management, Agile Methodology, Resource Allocation, Stakeholder Management, Oracle, HIVE, Big Data Test lead , Azure Data Engineering Test lead, Azure Data

Engineering Test Manager, Azure DevOps

Verified : Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

#### Summary

A Vibrant and an audacious professional with 14 years of IT experience in Data Engineering team. Always gear up in quest and quench of nabbing the challenging opportunities. I plunged into the streaks of different roles in IT industry like - Technical Project Manager, Scrum Master, E2E Test delivery lead

## **Work Experience**

■ **Dell International Services** as Technical Project Manager Data Engineering team

Dec 2010 to Till Date

Programs: PINE Program

Role: Technical Project Manager (TPM/ Scrum Master)

Team: Data Engineering Team
Duration: From Feb 2017 to till date

Roles and Responsibilities

Embark the project by building a communication channel between business stake holders and IT teams.

Defining the Project governance

Planning the overall project and monitoring the progress

Running Sprint planning calls and daily agile scrum meetings

Coordinating the projects, progress and their interdependencies

Collaborating with Development managers on resource allocations, utilizations across projects

Working with acquaintances in managing and monitoring the project budget

Managing Risk and Issues and taking corrective measurements

Daily project management throughout the Project/Program life cycle

Managing Stakeholders communications

Creating Project TFS dashboards

Aligning and delivering the MBI (outputs) to the program's "outcome" with the aid of TFS

Immaculately managing the Program Production releases

Programs: EMC Integration Program

PINE Program

Role: Technical Project Manager (TPM/ Scrum Master)

Team: Data Engineering Team
Duration: From Jan 2014 to Jan 2017

Roles and Responsibilities

Embark the project by building a communication channel between business stake holders and IT teams.

Defining the Project governance

Planning the overall project and monitoring the progress

Running Sprint planning calls and daily adile scrum meetings

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Coordinating the projects, progress and their interdependencies

Collaborating with Development managers on resource allocations, utilizations across projects

Working with acquaintances in managing and monitoring the project budget

Managing Risk and Issues and taking corrective measurements:

Daily project management throughout the Project/Program life cycle Managing Stakeholders communications

Creating Project TFS dashboards

Aligning and delivering the MBI (outputs) to the program's "outcome" with the aid of TFS

Immaculately managing the Program Production releases

Programs: EMC Integration Program PINE Program

Role: Technical Project Manager (TPM/Scrum Master)

Team: Data Engineering Team
Duration: From Jan 2014 to Jan 2017

## Roles and Responsibilities

Embark the project by building a communication channel between business stake holders and IT teams. Defining the Project governance

Planning the overall project and monitoring the progress Running Sprint planning calls and daily agile scrum meetings Coordinating the projects, progress and their interdependencies

Collaborating with Development managers on resource allocations, utilizations across projects

Working with acquaintances in managing and monitoring the project budget

Managing Risk and Issues and taking corrective measurements:
Daily project management throughout the Project/Program life cycle
Managing Stakeholders communications

Creating Project TFS dashboards

Aligning and delivering the MBI (outputs) to the program's "outcome" with the aid of TFS Immaculately managing the Program Production releases

Programs: Dell Print Commercial

Role: Scrum Master

Team: Data Engineering Team
Duration: From Nov 2012 to Dec 2013

Roles and Responsibilities

Coordination and collaboration with Product owners and IT teams

Daily agile scrum calls

Tracking Team velocity, Burndown metrics and deliverables

Release Management

Collaborating with cross functional feature team

Monitoring on Product progress

Managing Risk and Issues and taking corrective measurements:

Creating Feature team TFS dashboards

# Tech Mahindra as Senior Associate

Feb 2006 to Dec 2010

^ Back to Top

# **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Deccan College of Engineering and Technology, Hyderabad in 2005

^ Back to Top

## **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Windows and UNIX	
Informatica, OBIEE 11g	
Business Objects Reports	
Cognos, MSTR	
MSAS, Azure Data Analytics	
Oracle 9i, 10g, 11g, Teradata	
Greenplum (Data Lakes)	
Quality Center 9.2, Clear Quest	
Microsoft Test Manager (TFS)	
Streamsets, Kafka, HIVE	
Pig Latin	

^ Back to Top

#### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

"Back to Tob

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.